CIO Files of John L. Lewis, Pt. II: CIO General Files on Microfilm 5831 mf
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Rhode Island through West Virginia, 1937-1942 (Reel 14)
  - CIO--Virginia., 1940; 20 (Reel 14)
    37 pp.: CIO organizers and regional directors; 1940 US presidential campaigns of FDR and Wendell Willkie; Illinois Department of Mines and Minerals; support for CIO presidency of John L. Lewis; southern organizing campaign; Southern Conference for Human Welfare; legislative programs; Geyer anti-poll tax bill; Ben Williams's reminiscences of 1891 Mahaska County, Iowa, UMWA strike; 1940 state CIO convention; Thomas Hunter; Ray Thomason; Kathryn Lewis; A.D. Lewis; Frank P. Graham; Ora E. Gasaway; Ben Williams.
  - CIO--Virginia., 1941; 21 (Reel 14)
    36 pp.: Support for UMWA in captive mines dispute; National Defense Mediation Board; CIO organizers and regional directors; criticism of UAW in North American Aviation Co. strike in California; national defense mobilization efforts; Federation of Hosiery Workers strike and contract negotiations in Kingsport, TN; 1941 state CIO convention; Ray Thomason; Franklin D. Roosevelt; Ora E. Gasaway; Kathryn Lewis.
  - CIO--Virginia., 1942; 22 (Reel 14)
    5 pp.: Support for UMWA presidency of John L. Lewis.
  - CIO--Washington., 1937; 23 (Reel 14)
    23 pp.: Legislative programs; support for five-day work week; support for AFL-CIO unity negotiations; CIO organizers and regional directors; Labor's non-partisan league; political activities; SWOC; AFL-CIO competition; American Newspaper Guild strikes; CIO strike relief; financial matters; Richard Francis; Kathryn Lewis; Eli L. Oliver.
  - CIO--Washington--Seattle Committee for Industrial Organization., 1937; 24 (Reel 14)
    8 pp.: American Newspaper Guild strikes; CIO strike relief; competition with IBT; anti-CIO policies of city administration; support for AFL-CIO unity negotiations; CIO regional directors; Richard Francis.
  - CIO--Washington., 1938; 25 (Reel 14)
    42 pp.: CIO organizers and regional directors; company unions; press relations; 1938 state CIO convention; plans for Labor Day celebrations; UMWA district presidents; IWA; legislative programs; AFL-CIO competition; IBT labor racketeering; violence and intimidation; political activities; CIO-UMWA cooperation; radio broadcasts; Richard Francis; Walter Smethurst; Frank Hefferly; William J. Sneed; Eli L. Oliver.
  - CIO--Washington., 1939; 26 (Reel 14)
    35 pp.: CIO organizers and regional directors@United Construction Workers Organizing Committee; press relations; plans for 1940 UMWA convention; factionalism and internal politics; Communist activities; 1939 state CIO convention; ILWU; IWA; IUMMSW; UMWA district presidents; Speakers Bureau arrangements for Labor Day celebrations; support for AFL-CIO unity negotiations; A.D. Lewis; Richard Francis; David Fowler; Ora E. Gasaway; John Brophy.
  - CIO--Washington., 1940; 27 (Reel 14)
    115 pp.: 1940 state CIO convention; minutes of meetings of Seattle Industrial Labor Union Council; UMWA district presidents; CIO organizers and regional directors; Communist activities; legislative programs; Labor's Non-Partisan league; Washington Commonwealth Federation; IWA factionalism and internal politics; 1940 Washington State Democratic Convention; US Department of Labor; 1940 presidential campaigns of FDR and Wendell Willkie; factionalism and internal politics; 1940 UMWA convention; 1940 Oregon state CIO convention; controversy over activities of Adolph Germer; Richard Francis and William Dalrymple; support for CIO presidency of John L. Lewis; Harry Bridges; Richard Francis; Adolph Germer; John T. Jones; Eli L. Oliver; Kathryn Lewis; Allan S. Haywood; Lee Pressman; Len De Caux; A.D. Lewis; Harvey C. Fremming; Gola Whitlow.
  - CIO--Washington., 1941; 28 (Reel 14)
    84 pp.: CIO organizers and regional directors; formation of National War Labor Board; Office of Production Management. AFL-CIO competition; national defense mobilization efforts; support for UMWA in captive mines dispute; Communist activities; 1941 state CIO convention; factionalism and internal politics; IWA factionalism and internal politics; UMWA district presidents; shipbuilding situation in Oregon and Washington; political activities; Richard Francis; A.D. Lewis; Adolph Gremer; Harvey C. Fremming; Allan S. Haywood; Sidney Hillman.
  - CIO--Washington., 1942; 29 (Reel 14)
    34 pp.: 1942 state CIO convention; war mobilization efforts; political activities; summary of all state industrial union councils; Philip Murray; John Brophy; Richard Francis; Adolph Germer.
  - CIO--West Virginia., 1937; 30 (Reel 14)
    4 pp.: CIO organizers and regional directors; UMWA organizers; Adolph Pacifico.
  - CIO--West Virginia., 1938; 31 (Reel 14)
    77 pp.: Proposed organization of WPA workers; proceedings of the 1938 state CIO convention; AFL-CIO competition; AFL criticism of NLRB; AFL support of PMWA; UMWA district presidents; union organization; Kathryn Lewis; FDR; John B. Easton; William Blizzard; Van A. Bittner; William Green.
  - CIO--West Virginia., 1939; 32 (Reel 14)
    59 pp.: Press relations; 1939 state CIO convention; PWOC; educational programs; Workers Alliance of America; John B. Easton; Kathryn Lewis; A.D. Lewis; Ralph Hetzel.
  - CIO--West Virginia., 1940; 33 (Reel 14)
    86 pp.: CIO organizers and regional directors; UMWA district presidents; organization of WPA workers; national defense mobilization efforts; 1950 state CIO convention; legislative programs; anti-war sentiments; press relations; political activities; educational programs; women's auxiliaries; UMWA union organization; 1940 presidential campaigns of FDR and Wendell Willkie; support for CIO presidency of John L. Lewis; Joseph Angelo; C.F. Davis; Allan S. Haywood; John B. Easton; Kathryn Lewis; Franklin D. Roosevelt.
  - CIO--West Virginia., 1941; 34 (Reel 14)
    40 pp.: CIO organizers and regional directors; union organization; UMWA District 50; Labor Day arrangements; support for UMWA in captive mines dispute; National Defense Mediation Board; Joseph Angelo; Ora E. Gasaway; John B. Easton; Franklin D. Roosevelt.
  - CIO--West Virginia., 1942; 35 (Reel 14)
    31 pp.: UMWA conflict with CIO; UMWA non-payment of per capita to CIO; 1942 state CIO convention; UMWA district presidents; support for UMWA presidency of John L. Lewis; AFL-CIO unity negotiations; John B. Easton; George J. Titler; Philip Murray.
- Wisconsin through Wyoming, 1936-1942; AFL, 1929-1933 (Reel 15)
  - CIO--Wisconsin Provisional CIO Committee., 1936; 1 (Reel 15)
    2 pp.: 1936 state CIO convention; support for AFL-CIO unity negotiations.
  - CIO--Wisconsin Provisional CIO Committee., 1938; 2 (Reel 15)
    20 pp.: CIO organizers and regional directors; 1938 state CIO convention; factionalism and internal politics; UAW-CIO relations; support for AFL-CIO unity negotiations; AFL-CIO competition; 1938 Bricklayers, Masons, and Plasterers' International Union of America convention; press relations; CIO organization of building trades; National Progressive party and Senator Robert M. La Follette; Gunnar Mickelson; Kathryn Lewis; John Brophy; Emil Costello. CIO--Wisconsin.
  - CIO--Wisconsin., 1940; 3 (Reel 15)
    18 pp.: National defense mobilization efforts; strikes; support for CIO presidency of John L. Lewis; 1940 state CIO convention; NLRB; political activities; support for AFL-CIO unity negotiations; Walter J. Burke; Sidney Hillman; Harvy H. Kitzman.
  - CIO--Wisconsin., 1941; 4 (Reel 15)
    7 pp.: Support for UMWA in captive mines dispute; 1941 state CIO convention; Walter J. Burke.
  - CIO--Wisconsin., 1942; 5 (Reel 15)
    2 pp.: Criticism of UMWA District 50 organization of dairy farmers; war mobilization efforts.
  - CIO--Wyoming., 1937; 6 (Reel 15)
    2 pp.: See CIO--Utah file folders.
  - CIO--Wyoming., 1938; 7 (Reel 15)
    5 pp.: Support for AFL-CIO unity proposals of Daniel J. Tobin; CIO organizers and regional directors; UMWA district presidents; union organization in Wyoming and Utah; NLRB elections; James Morgan.
  - CIO--Wyoming., 1939; 8 (Reel 15)
    4 pp.: CIO organizers and regional directors; UMWA district presidents; James Morgan; Kathryn Lewis.
  - CIO--Wyoming., 1940; 9 (Reel 15)
    4 pp.: CIO organizers and regional directors; UMWA district presidents; union organization in Wyoming and Colorado; Oil Workers International Union; IUMMSW; UMWA organization; finding of dynamite in coal mines; James Morgan
  - CIO--Wyoming., 1941; 10 (Reel 15)
    3 pp.: Local union plans for a celebration.
  - CIO--Wyoming., 11 (Reel 15)
    Undated. 2 pp.: Support for AFL-CIO unity negotiations.
  - AFL. 1929., 12 (Reel 15)
    97 pp.: AFL volunteer organizers; AFL-UMWA cooperation; UMWA district presidents; UMWA organizers; southern organizing campaign@United Textile Workers; 1929 AFL convention; conference between labor officials and Herbert Hoover regarding US economic conditions and contract negotiations; radio broadcasts; state and local AFL organizations; America' Wage Earners Protective Conference; warning regarding Communist influence int eh international Labor Defense, Workers International Relief, and Conference for Progressive Labor Action; UMWA factionalism and internal politics; Reorganized United Mine Workers of America; William Green; O.F> Nigro; Frank Morrison; Philip Murray; Thomas Kennedy; Matthew Woll.
  - AFL. 1930., 13 (Reel 15)
    189 pp.: AFL volunteer organizers; AFL-UMWA cooperation; AFL state and local organizations; political activities; UMWA factionalism and internal politics; Reorganized United Mine Workers of America; criticism of UMWA presidency of John L. Lewis; insurgent UMWA District 12; US Senate rejection of appointment of John J. Parker as US Supreme Court nominee; 1930 AFL convention; legislative programs; southern organizing campaign; support for UMWA contract negotiations; UMWA v. Red Jacket Consolidated Coal and Coke Co. (US Circuit Court of Appeals for West Virginia, opinion by Judge John J. Parker); use of injunctions in labor disputes; 1930 UMWA convention; William Green; John H. Walker; Frank Morrison; Matthew Woll; Victor A. Olander; Henry Warrum; Paul J. Smith; Thomas Kennedy.
  - AFL. 1931., 14 (Reel 15)
    121 pp.: Legislative programs; unemployment relief efforts; 1931 AFL convention; AFL volunteer organizers; economic analysis of US coal industry; AFL state and local organizations; Communist influence in the National miners' Union; US Department of Commerce; US Senate investigation of unemployment; Reorganized United Mine Workers of America; insurgent UMWA District 12; use of injunctions in labor disputes; AFL executive council matters; Frank Morrison; Edward F. McGrady; William Green; Philip Murray; Matthew Woll; William Collins; Herbert Hoover.
  - AFL. 1932., 15 (Reel 15)
    224 pp.: 1932 AFL convention; PMWA; AFL state and local organizations; International Brotherhood of Paper Makers; Labor's National Committee for the Modification of the Volstead Act; Hotel and Restaurant Employees' and Beverage Dispensers' International Alliance; radio broadcasts; withdrawal of National Federation of Federal Employees from the AFL; founding of American Federation of Government Employees; insurgent UMWA District 12; use of injunctions in labor disputes; unemployment insurance proposals; legislative programs; AFL executive council matters; 1932 presidential campaign of FDR; educational programs; Labor Advisory Council of the American Legion National Employment Commission; National Brotherhood of Operative Potters; UMWA history of strikes in Mingo County, WV, and Alabama; UMWA benefit programs; Friends of the Soviet Union; UMWA district presidents; IBEW; Journeymen Barbers' International Union; AFL factionalism and internal politics; UMWA contract negotiations; criticism of AFL presidency of William Green; press relations; 1932 UMWA convention; William Green; Philip Murray; P.T. Fagan; Thomas Kennedy; Matthew J. Burns; Matthew Woll; Frank Morrison; Robert B. Hesketh; Paul J. Smith; James M. Duffy; Tom Mooney; O.F. Nigro; John B. Easton; G.M. Bugniazet; J.C. Shanessy; James Morgan; Lee Hall; William Turnblazer; Lee F. Hartman; Louis Adamic.
  - AFL. 1933., 16 (Reel 15)
    375 pp.: National Labor Board elections; Regional Labor Board decisions; AFL executive council matters; 1933 AFL convention; AFL volunteer organizers; UMWA organizers; company unions; unemployment relief programs; AFL state and local organizations; NRA code development and implementation; UMWA district presidents; legislative programs; International Hod Carriers' Building and Common Laborers' Union of America jurisdictional dispute with UMWA; Bricklayers, Masons, and Plasterers' International Union of America jurisdictional dispute with UMWA; organizing campaigns; FLU organization; Brotherhood of Railway and Steamship Clerks, Freight Handlers and Station Employees; political activities; Gallup, NM, coal miners' strike; ACLU; Workers Education Bureau of America; ACWA membership statistics; NRA; President's Reemployment Agreement; Brotherhood of Locomotive Firemen and Enginemen; IBEW; Labor's National Committee for Modification of the Volstead Act; press relations; appointment of Frances Perkins as US Secretary of Labor; International Printing Pressmen and Assistants' Union of North America; thirty-hour week legislation; John Fitzpatrick; William Green; Thomas Kennedy; Philip Murray; Matthew Woll; Van A. Bittner; Hugh S. Johnson; Joseph V. Moreschi; John J. Gleeson; Frank Morrison; George M. Harrison; Morris Hillquit; Roger N. Baldwin; D.B. Robertson; H.H. Broach; John H. Walker; George L. Berry; Victor A. Olander; Edward F. McGrady.
- AFL. 1934 -1935 (Reel 16)
  - AFL. 1934 [Part 1]., 1 (Reel 16)
    162 pp.: AFL volunteer organizers; founding of New England Council of Utility Workers; plans for 1934 AFL convention; Geneva Conference of the ILO; AFL state and local organizations; strikes; AFL-UMWA cooperation; NRA codes; UMWA district presidents; legislative programs; AFL general and district organizers; organizing campaigns; FLUs; 1934 UMWA convention; Regional Labor Board decisions; National Labor Board hearings; political activities; Philip Murray; Ray Edmundson; William Green; Frank Morrison; A.D. Lewis; Thomas Kennedy; Van A. Bittner; John B. Easton; R. Lee Guard; Matthew Woll; Martin Brennan; John Fitzpatrick.
  - AFL. 1934 [Part 2]., 2 (Reel 16)
    237 pp.: AFL Building Trades Department; 1934 AFL convention; political activities; AFL volunteer organizers; UMWA district presidents; AFL state and local organizations; AFL-UMWA cooperation; AFL factionalism and internal politics; unemployment programs; thirty-hour week proposals; UMWA organizers; Order of Sleeping Car Conductors; UMWA contract negotiations; legislative programs; support for industrial unionism; controversy over crafts unionism versus industrial unionism; UMWA support for United Textile Workers of America general strike; economic analysis of industrial conditions; AFL executive council matters; UMWA factionalism and internal politics@United Insurance Writers of America; NRA codes; William Green; William J. Sneed; Adolph Germer; Frank Morrison; George L. Berry; David J. McDonald; Matthew Woll; M.S. Warfield; A.D. Lewis; R. Lee Guard; Philip Murray; Thomas Kennedy; Van A. Bittner; Frank Farrington; John J. Mates.
  - AFL. 1935 [Part 1]., 3 (Reel 16)
    374 pp.: AFL volunteer organizers; UMWA district presidents; UMWA organizers; AFL-UMWA cooperations; AFL state and local organizations; legislative programs; National Labor Relations bill (Wagner bill); thirty-hour week proposals; political activities; controversy over crafts unionism versus industrial unionism; AFL executive council matters; AFL factionalism and internal politics; organization of black workers; AFL Building Trades Department; NRA codes; AFL general organizers; economic analysis of industrial conditions; Workers Education Bureau of America; radio broadcasts; criticism of AFL presidency of William Green; Regional Labor Board hearings; collective bargaining plan for the steel industry; South-Wide Labor Conference of Delegates from Central Bodies and State Federations of Labor; IUMMSW contract negotiations; history of AFL-IUMMSW relations; minutes of meetings of AFL executive council; organizing campaigns@United Textile Workers of America; proposed establishment of UAW; financial matters; membership of and payment of per capita by AFL affiliates; report on Communists and Communist activities within the trade union movement; Industrial Union of Marine and Shipbuilding Workers of America; William Green; William Mitch; Philip Murray; Thomas Kennedy; Henry Warrum; Earl E. Houck; Ellis Searles; A.D> Lewis; John Brophy; Ora E. Gasaway; C.S. Garrison; Charles P. Howard; David Dubinsky; J.C. Lewis; Frank B. Powers; Andrew A. Myrup; Frank Morrison; Ray Edmundson; Samuel Caddy; George L. Berry; Matthew Woll; Edward A. Filene; Henry Ford; P.T. Fagan; Adolph Germer; I.M. Ornburn; W.P. Stacey; George L. Googe; W.C. Roberts; Francis J. Haas; John Green; Philip H. Van Gelder.
  - AFL. 1935 [Part 2]., 4 (Reel 16)
    281 pp.: Proposed organization of unemployed and domestic workers; AFL-UMWA cooperation; AFL volunteer organizers; UMWA district presidents; AFL executive council matters; legislative programs; support for New Deal legislation; AFL state and local organizations; minutes of meetings of AFL executive council; unemployment insurance and relief proposals; organization of aluminum, steel, and auto workers; jurisdictional dispute between International Brewery Workers and IBT; National Union for Social Justice; IUMMSW jurisdictional dispute with AFL Metal Trades Department; controversy over crafts unionism versus industrial unionism; FLUs; Akron, Ohio, Rubber workers strike; financial matters; membership of and payment of per capita by AFL affiliates; AFL general and district organizers; AFL and UMWA factionalism and internal politics; International Federation of Trade Unions financial matters; US Supreme Court decision overturning the NIRA; National Labor relations bill (Wagner bill); AFL Building Trades Department; William Green; James Mark; Frank Morrison; Franklin D. Roosevelt; Percy Tetlow; P.T. Fagan; Joseph V. Moreschi; M.F. Tighe; Charles E. Coughlin; A.O. Wharton; Charles P. Howard; Michael J. Colleran; Andrew A. Myrup; Daniel W. Tracy; Robert J. Watt; Matthew Woll; John A. Phillips; John Possehl; Dan Moley; John P. Frey; Steve Nance; George M. Harrison; Luigi Antonini; Selma Borchardt; Kitty Donelly; Thomas H. Brown; Frank Duffy; G.M. Bugniazet; William L. Hutcheson; Daniel J. Tobin; George L. Berry; David Dubinski; Joseph N. Weber; Tom Mooney; Charlton Ogburn.
- AFL. 1935 -1945 (Reel 17)
  - AFL. 1935 [part 3]., 1 (Reel 17)
    258 pp.: 1935 AFL convention; controversy over crafts unionism versus industrial unionism; founding of CIO; an analysis of the mandates of the 1934 AFL convention showing what the convention voted should be done and what the AFL actually did; legislative programs; minutes of meetings of AFL executive council; financial matters; membership of and payment of per capita by AFL affiliates; suspension of CIO affiliates by AFL executive council; AFL-UMWA tension; UMWA organizers; American League against War and Fascism; AFL volunteer organizers; UMWA district presidents; AFL local and state organizations; resignation of John L. Lewis from AFL vice-presidency; AFL factionalism and internal politics; unemployment insurance and relief proposals; support for boycott of German-made products; AFL general and district organizers; Guffey-Snyder Coal Stabilization Act; organization of black workers; AFL Metal Trades Department; Labor 's Non-Partisan League; AFL Building Trades Department; lawsuits; Charles P. Howard; David Dubinsky; J.C. Lewis; Frank B. Powers; Andrew A. Myrup; Frank Morrison; William Green;Selma Boarchardt; P.T. Fagan; I.M. Ornburn; Harold L. Ickes; Samuel Caddy; Ray Edmundson; Angelo Herndon; Thomas F. Ryan; William Mitch; Thomas Kennedy; David Fowler; John Brophy; John P. Frey; George L. Berry; Harry S. Truman; Frank Feeney; M.J. McDonough; William J. McSorley; A.O. Wharton; John Coefield; William C. O'Neill; James W. Williams; John Possehl; Richard J. Gray; Daniel W. Tracy; William McCarthy; Herbert Rivers; Thomas L. Hughes; Joseph V. Moreschi.
  - AFL. 1936., 2 (Reel 17)
    101 pp.: UMWA controversy with AFL over establishment of CIO; criticism of UMWA presidency of John L. Lewis; criticism of AFL presidency of William Green; suspension of CIO affiliates by AFL executive council; AFL district and general organizers; AFL Metal Trades Department presentation of charges against CIO affiliates before AFL executive council; SWOC; UMWA payment of per capita to AFL; UMWA organizers; labor planks submitted by the AFL to the 1936 Republican National convention; labor planks in the 1936 political platforms of Republican and Democratic parties; AFL volunteer organizers; UMWA district presidents; AFL Building Trades Department; 1936 convention dates of AFL national and international affiliates; AFL housing and legislative programs; William Green; Walter Smethurst; A.D. L Lewis; Paul J. Smith; Philip Murray; Charles P. Howard; Sidney Hillman; Luigi Antonini; Thomas F. McMahon; Harvey C. Fremming; E.C. Conarty; Max Zaritsky; Thomas H. Brown; Glen W. McCabe; M.F. Tighe; Homer Martin; Sherman H. Dalrymple; Thomas Kennedy; Nicholas Fontenecchio; Frank Morrison; G.M. Bugniazet; Thomas A. Rickert; Matthew Woll; Felix H. Knight; David Fowler; P.T. Fagan; John M. Ross; Harry C. Bates; John Coefield; Michael J. Colleran; Frank Barnhart.
  - AFL. 1937., 3 (Reel 17)
    17 pp.: AFL-CIO controversy; support for AFL-CIO unity negotiations; AFL news releases; AFL-UMWA controversy; AFL executive council matters; UMWA expulsion of AFL president William Green; AFL legislative programs; William Green; Frank Morrison.
  - AFL. 1938., 4 (Reel 17)
    98 pp.: AFL-CIO controversy; proceedings of the 1938 AFL convention; AFL legislative programs; NLRB; criticism of CIO chairmanship of John L. Lewis; criticism of AFL presidency of William Green; jurisdictional dispute between the Allied Printing Trades Unions and the International Lithographers Protective and Beneficial Association; William Green; Nathan Straus; FDR; Adolph Germer; A.D. Lewis; David W. Davis; Joseph C. Orr.
  - AFL. 1939., 5 (Reel 17)
    50 pp.: AFL-CIO peace conferences and unity negotiations; newsclippings; US Department of Labor; summaries of meetings; AFL and CIO peace proposals; CIO executive board matters; The CIO News; 1939 AFL convention; proposals for mass CIO union organization campaigns; AFL-PMWA cooperation; Frances Perkins; Philip Murray; Ralph Hetzel; Len De Caux; Pat McCarren; Kathryn Lewis; James Mark; Gardner Jackson.
  - AFL. 1940., 6 (Reel 17)
    58 pp.: Digest of proceedings of 1940 AFL convention; 1940 US presidential campaigns of FDR and Wendell Willkie; criticism of CIO presidency of John L. Lewis; Smith Committee of the US Congress; NLRB; AFL-CIO unity negotiations; William Green.
  - AFL. 1941., 7 (Reel 17)
    51 pp.: AFL-CIO unity negotiations; AFL Metal Trades Department; national defense mobilization efforts; digest of proceedings of 1941 AFL convention; William L. Hutcheson; John P. Frey.
  - AFL. 1942., 8 (Reel 17)
    91 pp.: Digest of proceedings of 1942 AFL convention; UMWA position regarding AFL-CIO unity negotiations; CIO factionalism and internal politics; CIO executive board matters; AFL policy regarding AFL-CIO unity negotiations; history of AFL-CIO unity negotiations; Welly K. Hopkins; Joseph A. Padway; Matthew Woll; Philip Murray; William Green; FDR.
  - AFL. 1943., 9 (Reel 17)